# (416) 786-1502 brianduffield@gmail.com

# **Brian Duffield**

Toronto, Ontario linkedin.com/in/brianduffieldtoronto brianduffield.github.io

# **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Highly experienced and versatile IT professional specializing in technical documentation with a keen focus on product development. More than 15 years of experience as a professional writer and manager, working in the Enterprise and Cloud software industry. Proven ability to create accurate documentation for highly technical audiences as well as general software users. Demonstrated talent for working on multiple projects, with multiple stakeholders, under demanding deadlines. Thoroughly familiar with Agile software development environment and documentation's role within it.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# <u>Product Documentation and Training Manager</u> (*Tier1 Financial Solutions Application Suite*)

Tier1 Financial Solutions (formerly Tier1CRM)
Oct 2018 - Apr 2020

Promoted to documentation manager supporting existing and new products developed on the Salesforce CRM. Content developed by the team included user guides, online help, and release documentation for end-users, administrators, deployment teams, and developers, as well as training modules.

- Managed a team of four writers to support multiple Tier1 products on rapid release and patch cycles.
- Created a standardized template for Tier1's native API paths (endpoints) and attributes (parameters; the Tier1 APIs deliver customization and functionality to the product suite.
- Delivered a Product Documentation Team road map to executive management, which included goals to improve the product, product documentation, and delivery.
- Created initial drafts of critical Developer documentation for Tier1's new development platform,
   Tier1 Ellipsis Framework.
- Worked closely with UX manager, and team, to standardize the Tier1 application suite's labeling and microcopy, as well as contributed to UX Design Style Guide.
- Managed team to design and create the product training modules delivered to the Tier1 Academy team using D2L library management system (LMS).

# <u>Senior Product and Documentation Specialist</u> (ACE Tempo and ACE Investment Calendar)

Tier1 Financial Solutions (formerly Tier1CRM)
Jan 2018 - Oct 2018

Hired into a small financial software company to provide documentation and help support for several product lines built on Salesforce CRM and serving the Capital Markets.

- Developed release documentation within an Agile software development environment using Broadcom Rally; engaged in daily standups, sprint planning, story grooming, user story creation, and retrospectives.
- Delivered User Guide, Release Notes, and What's New content in PDF format, per release; uploaded user guide content in MadCap Flare TopNav format to Tier1's Knowledge Portal.
- Assisted QA team in ad hoc product testing, logging bugs, as well as proposing product design improvements to Product Management team.
- Worked on other documentation projects, as requested, including configuration/API documentation, marketing copy, and internal process guides.

# Product and Documentation Specialist

# Pulse Systems, Feb 2016 - Dec 2017

(PulseCloud EHR / Pulse Mobile)

Worked on a small team of technical communication professionals to provide documentation and online help support for Pulse Systems' healthcare software.

- Developed documentation within an Agile software development environment using JIRA;
   participated fully in sprint planning, daily standups, feature planning, pointing sessions, user story creation, and retrospectives.
- Modernized Pulse Cloud's online help system by implementing a MadCap Flare TopNav format, including customized JavaScript; integrated our help files with development in GIT for source control.
- Proposed an architectural improvement to the product by de-coupling the online help from the development builds; worked with technical architecture team to implement.
- Focused aggressively on improving the product; logging over 200 bug and enhancement tickets for PulseCloud, improving functionality and addressing UI/UX issues.

### **Documentation Manager**

### Oracle Canada, Mar 2006 - Jun 2015

(Oracle Fusion Middleware / Oracle Fusion Applications / Siebel CRM Platform / Oracle Mobile) Managed documentation teams within Oracle focused on developer and platform documentation. Content included installation, development, customization, server admin, tools, security, APIs, help systems, and mobile frameworks. See: <a href="http://docs.oracle.com">http://docs.oracle.com</a>.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Technical writing and graphics tools including MadCap Flare, Adobe FrameMaker and Structured FrameMaker, and Adobe Acrobat; familiar with Markdown and other editors.
- Project management experience with Confluence, wikis, JIRA, and Rally; experience with Agile tools and methodology; experience with source-control systems SVN, GIT, and SDL.
- Familiar with API documentation tools, such as cURL, Postman, Git, GitHub, Stoplight, Swagger editor, as well as OpenAPI specification.
- Salesforce CRM Classic and Lighting; Salesforce Trailhead Adventurer status (19 badges); Tier1 Financial Solutions AFR configuration and Ellipsis Framework experience.
- Internet design experience with XML, HTML, HTML5, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, and other scripting languages; knowledge of relational databases and SQL, including experience with Oracle standard, XE, and MySQL databases.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Co-author of ARMA (American Record Management Association) technical report on mobile communications and security (Mobile Communications and Records and Information Management -ARMA TR-20-2012 – ISBN ISBN: 978-1-936654-08-6, published in 2012).
- LinkedIn Article: Help When You Need It.
- Published in National Post, Globe and Mail, Society of Technical Communications (STC) Intercom Magazine, and other publications.

# **EDUCATION**

- Computer Science Certificate Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario
- Bachelor of Engineering (Civil) Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario
- Bachelor of Science (Mathematics) Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia